I do not work on an organ; I always work on an environment.
And I'm very careful not to be too selective, too localized.
When we look at the liver, it also organizes both the posterior cavity of the omentum
as well as the positioning of the stomach, ultimately the axis for the spleen,
and even eventually to the greater omentum.
We will practice on the liver in relation to the heart
and in relation to the posterior cavity of the omentum, but with a different approach.
Simply allowing the liver to regain its motility,
because it's what ultimately creates its function.
We start; it’s a neutral touch, still somewhat superficial.
But the deeper the neutral touch is, the more the primary breath reveals itself.
It's really this encounter of these two neutrals that brings forth the therapeutic process.
We've seen the importance of the liver.
It organizes the embryo as well,
in its transverse axis, with the formation of what we call the axis
gastro-duodenal-pancreatic-lienal,
all this movement, and so it will give rise to all this motion like this.
This tipping that you began to understand yesterday with the venous and arterial network,
is a developmental movement in growth, which
is why it indeed moves in that direction.
But it does not rotate on itself.
So it has this force of development.
And that is the motility of embryonic origin.
When we place our hands, we will be more in a fulcrum
where the whole system develops.
If I focus locally, I leave the original fulcrum.
The closer you get to the embryonic fulcrum, the closer you get to this force,
the more the body can give you information.
Because it knows.
So, the higher its frequency, the more regenerative power is enacted.
Take the word “fulcrum” as well; it’s a function.
The midline, for example, is a fulcrum for the whole.
But the fulcrum can also act as a point of support; there are also mobile fulcrums.
I prefer a functional term.
We saw the heart area where I said, “this is the fulcrum, this is its arrival.”
And thus, this is the embryonic fulcrum.
I can't say it’s a point.
This good work of the tib...
of brain development, we can use it almost as a tool.
Remember these curves, the tai chi of the brain, expansion, flexion
of the cephalic,
cervical flexion, pontine flexion, and
teleencephalization.
This phase of teleencephalization is very important.
It brings about the straightening phase and the entire establishment of my anterior white line.
That’s why the sternum means both the star, which is formed like this
and like this.
We can work solely on its motility, or we can take specific points,
which are points of support, like the tip of my notochord, like the supra-occiput,
like the base of the occiput or the sphenoid, which will relate to its developments.
For example, the tip...
will be one of the important reference points in sub-mesencephalic flexion, and so I can
search for the point of silence in the developing system; this will depend
on the support points where I will place myself; there are phases that will occur together, it’s
the synchronicities of development regarding this brain development, the significant
vestige
will be found at the level of the mesenteric system, and we see here that we have an
axis
vitelline or mesaraic, you see, that will emerge.
That means sometimes, we need to seek out
what happened at that level,
as a reference, as a plan,
to revitalize a developing brain, for example,
at a vascular level.
Don’t forget that the brain is completely dependent
on its function and formation from the heart.
It continuously informs it
and we find a pulsation in the brain.
Always good...
We see this image here; we see this transverse septum that wraps around with
the establishment of the liver, etc., that would be integrated with this vitelline sac.
The formation of this amniotic cavity, which is all the work we did yesterday,
there's a developmental motility movement generated by the liver and
which will establish the entire hepato-gastro-duodenopancreatic
-lienal system.
Both the tipping of the heart, we might say, on its left axis,
this reverse movement at
the hepatic level, globally, and the counter-rotation on
the digestive plane. There, you have the points
of support, and we will just work first on this large center of subdiaphragmatic organization,
with all the setup finally of the ARKVT of the omentum, then we will see how it
will
present itself in relation to my liver.
and the heart; these will be our two points of focus.
The cardiac imprint, the pulmonary imprint, and the huge hepatic imprint.
We will work on the liver in relation to the establishment of the heart and the intestines
and we will engage in a process with the idea of this biodynamics.
That is, we will place our hands and allow the movement to occur.
And there, we can have a movement that comes seeking, or we can have a movement that shows its originality.
We will provide.
this point for the system to reorganize itself.
The liver, in fact, is a specialization of the digestive tube.
It should be seen as a fractal expansion of the intestine.
It is a set of bile ducts with two types of information.
One type of vascular information, that’s where you have what we call the portal liver.
A completely red face can express a mesodermal liver problem.
An always pale face can explain an endodermal liver issue, these
are two ways of viewing the system.